<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Some Notes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://notes.whitepinedev.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 19:21:48 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 19:21:48 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Fall of the Ottomans by Eugene Rogan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruler a vast swath of land the Ottomans fought hard against the English,
French and Russians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forcing the English to retreat from the dardanelles, forcing the surrender of
almost 13,000 soldiers in Kut-al-Amara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were able to fight back the Russians and out of fear they massacered
the large number of their own Armenian citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/03/02/ottoman.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/03/02/ottoman.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Man Who Invented the Computer by Jane Smiley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Attanasof lived an interesting life from creating machines to measure the
seismic waves of the bikini atoll bomb testing to creating a computer with an in
program memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book told some of the story of other pioneers, Alan Turing, Konrad Zuse and
others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creators of the Eniac, Eckert, Mauchly and Neumann. And the controversial
court ruling that Attanasof’s creation was proof of prior art preventing 20 years
of stifling innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is amazing what human beings can create&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/23/invented-computer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/23/invented-computer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Fly Trap by Fredrik Sjöberg</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Intertwining his own story about the study of hover flies with the story of Malaise
created a beautiful book. I came away feeling like I had read some great insights
about living a life. What I did read was a good story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story of the love of hover flies, or more accurately the study of hover flies.
His description of how one can learn to read nature like learning to read a language.
Knowing the species of plants, animals their activities gives you a deeper
glimpse then just walking through it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a life Malaise lived journeying to Russia, Japan, Burma his marriages and
then his fascination with atlantis and then becoming a collector of paintings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of which the author became an owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What an enjoyable book!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/13/fly-trap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/13/fly-trap.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Age of Reason Begins by Will Durant</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Queen Elizabeth 1533 to 1603&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts between Catholics, Protestants, the rise of the puritans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defeat of the Spansih Armada, and England becoming a greater world power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/10/age-reason.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/10/age-reason.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Philosophy of Mind by Patrick Grim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence, good old fashioned logic and algorithim based or building a simulation of a brain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is consciousness?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is consciousness subjective or objective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you study a subjective thing such as consciousness with an objective science?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/08/philosophy-mind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/02/08/philosophy-mind.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alone on the Ice By David Roberts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Shackleton, Scott the great arctice exploreres but one of the most accomplished explorers was Dawson
of the AAE who established 2 bases wintered over and had 8 expeditions out exploringing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His party met with a terrible accident Nimitz dying with all their supplies down a crevice, the second dying on their way back
and Dawson arriving 5 hours after the boat left so he and the others had to wait another winter for rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating tale of survival, strength and perserverence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/20/alone-ice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/20/alone-ice.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Islam and the Future of Tolerance By Sam Harris, Maajid Nawaz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What a great dialogue.  Very glad these two got together and shared their view points.&lt;br /&gt;
The QA section at the end of the audio book was also very enlightening&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/10/islam-tolerance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/10/islam-tolerance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Kids By Robert D. Putnam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Obviously the opportunities for children in poor families are much less then for children in more affluent families. This has always been the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is the difference getting worse?  Is upward mobility as accessible as it was to our parents and grandparents?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference in education is stark in many areas. Extracurricular programs, parental involvement, college enrollment, school culture and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the Troy and Santa Ana high schools makes the differences easy to see. At Troy there is a culture of doing well in school, parental involvement, donated money for extra programs. Santa Ana is full of poor families, parents or Grandparents with little education and little time to help. Kids just trying to survive let alone learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better parenting, reduce single parents, better community, more volunteering, different forms of teaching see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2013/10/free-thinkers/&quot;&gt;the recent wired article&lt;/a&gt;, more funding for after school programs, decriminalize drugs, rehabilitation instead of punishment, the importance of preschool education and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an interesting book, one that made me grateful for what I have, and one that made me want to do more to help those around me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/02/our-kids.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/02/our-kids.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The China Mirage by James Bradley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What if the war against Japan could have been avoided or delayed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100,000 Americans died in the Pacific theater of WWII. James Bradley proposes it didn’t need to happen. Maybe the Korean and Vietnam wars could have been avoided as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He describes the disaster that happened and explains how it could have been avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1800’s the opium trade began to reverse the flow of money into to China back to England and America. It was outlawed in China but England and America used their Navies and the unequal treaties China was forced to sign to keep the trade open. Many north eastern American’s made their fortunes from the trade, including the Delano family, FDR’s Grandpa made a fortune while young, lost it all and then went back in his 50’s and made a bigger one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprising how much of the money used to industrialize and create the northeast was from fortunes made in the opiate trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans began to believe that a New China would arise led by a Noble Peasant. Chinese who believed in Democracy and were big fans of America. This idea was fed and created by the Christian Missionaries who in reality had little success, then Mr Luce from the times magazine who fabricated many ‘facts’.  And the New China Lobby.  The Soong family who was educated in America, and particularly Chiang who was portrayed as the new leader of China.  They ended up getting more funding then America spent on getting the bomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting off oil to Japan led to them attacking us in Pearl Harbor. FDR’s freezing of Japan’s assets and limiting them to octanes below 87 should have allowed them access to oil from California still, but Acheson and others from the new china lobby bounced the Japanese from one bureaucracy to the next and effectively the subordinates of FDR cut them off from oil. Something FDR had said he did not want to do, but when he found out he didn’t reverse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mao led the people rebellion taking land from corrupt landlords, giving it to the peasants and creating schools including schools for women. He was very popular among the people and made several overtures to the US. Stillwell in the military from the US was convinced that America was backing the wrong man by helping Chiang and ignoring Mao. Ambassador Hurley got Stillwell fired and a voice of reason was lost. As was an opportunity to have normal relations with China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chiang lost battle after battle with Mao, and in 1949 Mao won. America wouldn’t have normal relations with china until Nixon’s visit. What a lost opportunity to open a dialogue, to communicate and work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book re-emphasized that you can’t trust the press, you can’t trust lobby groups, and you can’t trust officials or bureaucracy to truly have America or the worlds best interests at heart. Maintain your skepticism about everything you read and if you decide to create an opinion on a subject, support that opinion with facts from sources that can be trusted. Easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/31/mirage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/31/mirage.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ghost In My Brain by Clark Elliot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brain damage, it can reveal how the brain works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thread or processes of thought. We have constant streams of information coming into our brain.  How do we filter out what we want to pay attention to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how do we process the audio and visual inputs to come to an understanding of what is around us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we decide what to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author suffered a concussion and for 8 years struggled with brain damage that effected every aspect of his life.  He kept notes about it.  No one could help him until he found doctor Zelinksy who had special glasses that helped retrain the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/29/ghost.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/29/ghost.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
