<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Some Notes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://notes.whitepinedev.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 07:51:29 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 07:51:29 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Kids By Robert D. Putnam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Obviously the opportunities for children in poor families are much less then for children in more affluent families. This has always been the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is the difference getting worse?  Is upward mobility as accessible as it was to our parents and grandparents?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference in education is stark in many areas. Extracurricular programs, parental involvement, college enrollment, school culture and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the Troy and Santa Ana high schools makes the differences easy to see. At Troy there is a culture of doing well in school, parental involvement, donated money for extra programs. Santa Ana is full of poor families, parents or Grandparents with little education and little time to help. Kids just trying to survive let alone learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better parenting, reduce single parents, better community, more volunteering, different forms of teaching see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2013/10/free-thinkers/&quot;&gt;the recent wired article&lt;/a&gt;, more funding for after school programs, decriminalize drugs, rehabilitation instead of punishment, the importance of preschool education and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an interesting book, one that made me grateful for what I have, and one that made me want to do more to help those around me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 19:27:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/02/our-kids.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2016/01/02/our-kids.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The China Mirage by James Bradley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What if the war against Japan could have been avoided or delayed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100,000 Americans died in the Pacific theater of WWII. James Bradley proposes it didn’t need to happen. Maybe the Korean and Vietnam wars could have been avoided as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He describes the disaster that happened and explains how it could have been avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1800’s the opium trade began to reverse the flow of money into to China back to England and America. It was outlawed in China but England and America used their Navies and the unequal treaties China was forced to sign to keep the trade open. Many north eastern American’s made their fortunes from the trade, including the Delano family, FDR’s Grandpa made a fortune while young, lost it all and then went back in his 50’s and made a bigger one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprising how much of the money used to industrialize and create the northeast was from fortunes made in the opiate trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans began to believe that a New China would arise led by a Noble Peasant. Chinese who believed in Democracy and were big fans of America. This idea was fed and created by the Christian Missionaries who in reality had little success, then Mr Luce from the times magazine who fabricated many ‘facts’.  And the New China Lobby.  The Soong family who was educated in America, and particularly Chiang who was portrayed as the new leader of China.  They ended up getting more funding then America spent on getting the bomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting off oil to Japan led to them attacking us in Pearl Harbor. FDR’s freezing of Japan’s assets and limiting them to octanes below 87 should have allowed them access to oil from California still, but Acheson and others from the new china lobby bounced the Japanese from one bureaucracy to the next and effectively the subordinates of FDR cut them off from oil. Something FDR had said he did not want to do, but when he found out he didn’t reverse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mao led the people rebellion taking land from corrupt landlords, giving it to the peasants and creating schools including schools for women. He was very popular among the people and made several overtures to the US. Stillwell in the military from the US was convinced that America was backing the wrong man by helping Chiang and ignoring Mao. Ambassador Hurley got Stillwell fired and a voice of reason was lost. As was an opportunity to have normal relations with China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chiang lost battle after battle with Mao, and in 1949 Mao won. America wouldn’t have normal relations with china until Nixon’s visit. What a lost opportunity to open a dialogue, to communicate and work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book re-emphasized that you can’t trust the press, you can’t trust lobby groups, and you can’t trust officials or bureaucracy to truly have America or the worlds best interests at heart. Maintain your skepticism about everything you read and if you decide to create an opinion on a subject, support that opinion with facts from sources that can be trusted. Easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/31/mirage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/31/mirage.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ghost In My Brain by Clark Elliot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brain damage, it can reveal how the brain works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thread or processes of thought. We have constant streams of information coming into our brain.  How do we filter out what we want to pay attention to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how do we process the audio and visual inputs to come to an understanding of what is around us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we decide what to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author suffered a concussion and for 8 years struggled with brain damage that effected every aspect of his life.  He kept notes about it.  No one could help him until he found doctor Zelinksy who had special glasses that helped retrain the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/29/ghost.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/12/29/ghost.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Thin Green Line</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between wealthy and rich?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What effect does wealth have on a person?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of saving, budgeting, not overextending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then raising your children to understand how to use money and how to live a rich life vs just a wealthy one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/11/23/thin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/11/23/thin.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Boys in the Boat by Daniel James Brown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From Sequim to Berlin the story of some humans winning a race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe certainly didn’t have it easy. His mother dying, his new step mom convincing his dad to leave Joe behind when they moved during the Great Depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He worked hard, made it into UW and on the crew team.  What a story he and the other boys created. They worked hard in school and on the boat. Their coach Al was impressed and there was a rivalry between Washington and California.  California had gone to the 28 and 32 Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UW team won some tough races and made it to the Olympics. Their they won gold by a quarter of a second.  What a race it was rowing faster then they have ever rowed before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/11/22/boys.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/11/22/boys.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>History of Western Philosophy By Bertrand Russell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It begins with the Greeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tiny area of the Mediterranean produced the founders of western philosophy and thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pythagoras - don’t eat beans! 
Anaxagoras - Sun at the center.
Heraclitus - ever present change.
The Sophists:
Protagoras: “Man is the measure of all things”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socrates, Plato:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal.  The idea is real, what we have a see around us are inferior copies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The republic:
An idea for the ‘perfect city’  no one knew who their parents were, children raised and taught in groups, leaders selected from among the best. Women educated in the same way as men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spinoza, Hume, Leibniz, Kant and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book provided an interesting summary of western thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some philosophers had ideas that ended up having a huge negative effect, other ideas were useful, others were just plainly wrong when tested scientifically.  What is left for philosophy to examine now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found it interesting as the scientific revolution came along he included the great thinkers like Galileo.  Testable hypothesis have come to over-ride philosophical thinking. Are we missing things in our culture and society because of that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/11/10/betradnd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/11/10/betradnd.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1491 By Charles C Mann</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Re-examining what the America’s were like before contact with the old world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clovis culture 13,000 years ago, evidence of even older habitation in south America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Homburg mistake: taking a remnant of survivors as representative of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devastation caused by the loss of maybe 90% of the population. Reports of numerous towns and large populations and then 50 years later a depopulated place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A landscape that was a giant farm, trees, grasslands maintained by the natives with fire and plantings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aztec and Inca conquest. Tenochtitlan was bigger then Paris when it was conquered and had sewer systems and was quite the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mayan cities and their battles for supremacy. The Hopewell culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What philosophies and ideas were destroyed when their cultures and traditions were destroyed? No one can read the Inca knot writing. Most of the books were burned by the Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crops of the world were changed by what the American’s had domesticated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/10/25/1491.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/10/25/1491.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hitch 22 by Christopher Hitchens</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A man trying to change the world with words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A socialist from Oxford goes to Cuba, discovers it was another totalitarian regime. His mother left his father and eventually committed suicide. He ends up becoming an American citizen, supporting the war in Iraq and becoming one to the “New Athiests”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/10/14/hitch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/10/14/hitch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Origins of Life by Robert M Hazen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Competing theories abound, from a scaffolding on clay/crystal to a genetic origin in a RNA world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating how life could have arisen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/10/06/origin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/10/06/origin.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Changes Everything by Naomi Klein</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Capitalism vs The Environment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will we work to save the planet? Some progress has been made but we are losing the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans continue to pump out climate changing gases that are going to alter our climate dramatically. This is a threat to our way of life but it seems that humans aren’t taking it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is hope, but we have wasted the last decade. Lets work together and keep fossil fuels in the ground and switch to renewable resources that won’t destroy our world.  Some countries have made remarkable progress, others not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/09/27/change.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://notes.whitepinedev.com/notes/books/2015/09/27/change.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
